Otto Klemperer Archive
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1915-1971 (Box 1-43, 103-106, 108)
  - Works by Otto Klemperer (Box 1-37, 103-106, 108)
    - Adagio für grosses Orchester, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 11.1.69 Z. (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Adagio für grosses Orchester, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1969. (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Adagio no. 2, Copyist's manuscript for piano with corrections (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Adagio no. 2, Copyist's manuscript for piano (transparencies) (Box-folder 1/6)
    - An einen Verschwender, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 3.12.47 Zürich. (Box-folder 1/7)
    - An einen Verschwender, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1967. (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Andante für Sextett, Copyist's manuscript full score; On p. 1: 1969. (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Andante für Sextett, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Andante für Sextett, Parts (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Aria (Sehnsucht), Photocopy of copyist's manuscript; On p. 1: comp. 1948 in Budapest. At end: L. Montag Bp. 1976.III.10. Laid in: two letters and program. (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Aus dem Dunkel, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/1)
    - Ave Maria, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 12.1.69 Z. (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Ave Maria, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1969. (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Bathseba, 6. Bild, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score with corrections in Italian text; Laid in: libretto. (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Bathseba, 6. Bild, Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (Box-folder 103/1)
    - Bauern unter der Linde see Faust I Bauern unter der Linde
    - Benedictus, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: September 13, 1936, Los Angeles. (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Benedictus, Holograph manuscript sketch (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Berçeuse, Copyist's manuscript for violin and piano; On t.p.: 1905. (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Berçeuse, Photocopy of printed score (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Berçeuse, Violin part (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Caprice, Photocopy of holograph manuscript for piano; On t.p.: Original bei: Marcel Mihalovici, 15 rue du Dragon, Paris (6). (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Divertimento, Holograph manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1968. At end: 3.5.68 Z. (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Divertimento, Copyist's manuscript score (transparencies) (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Divertimento, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript score (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Divertimento, Parts (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Empfindungen beim Wiedersehen einer vielgeliebten Stadt, Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations; On t.p.: No. 3 [4 crossed out]; orchestration in German. At end: komponiert/ 1910 Frankfurt a/M 1911 instrumentiert Feldafing. (Box-folder 103/2)
    - Empfindungen beim Wiedersehen einer vielgeliebten Stadt, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Empfindungen beim Wiedersehen einer vielgeliebten Stadt, Photocopy of copyist's vocal part (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Es ist gut, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 30.1.68 Z. (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Es ist gut, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1968. (Box-folder 2/2)
    - [Faust] see also [Lieder] Es war einmal ein König (Box-folder 2/3-9)
      - Aus Faust, Holograph manuscript full score; Laid in: printed statement in German. (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Faust, Copyist's manuscript organ-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Faust I Bauern unter der Linde, Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Musik zu Faust, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Osterchöre Faust, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: ca. 1960. (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Faust-Musik: Oberon & Titanias goldene Hochzeit oder Walpurgisnachtstraum, [1. Fassung], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 30. Juni 1915 gegen Abend. Hamburg. Laid in: notes in German. (Box-folder 2/8)
      - Faust-Musik: Oberon & Titanias goldene Hochzeit, 2. Fassung, Holograph manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1968. At end: 7.1.68 Z. (Box-folder 2/9)
    - [Fugato, strings], Holograph manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1958. At end: 9.8.58 Gils-Maria D.L.G. (Box-folder 2/10)
    - [Fugato, strings], Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (Box-folder 2/11)
    - [Fugato, strings], Photocopy of copyist's full score with emendations (Box-folder 2/12)
    - [Fugato, strings], Photocopy of copyist's full score (Box-folder 2/13)
    - [Fugato, strings], Parts (transparencies) (Box-folder 2/14)
    - [Fugato, strings], Parts with emendations (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Fuge für grosses Orchester, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 3. März 1970 Zürich. (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Fuge für grosses Orchester, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1970. (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Gebet see also Lieder: Gebet, Holograph manuscript sketch (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Gebet: Herr, lass mich hungern, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 4.2.68 London. (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Gebet: Herr, lass mich hungern, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1968. (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 16.8.1969 Zürich. (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1969. (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich [version 1], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 23.10.69 London. (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich [Version 2], Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1969. (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich [version 3], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 4.1.70 Zürich. (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich [version 3], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: 1970. (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Geistliches Kampflied, Holograph manuscript full score; On t.p.: (April 1917 Strassburg). On p. 1: Dem Andenken des Leutnant Rudi Kohnstamm gewidmet der im Sommer 1916 vor Verdun fiel. At end: 17. April 1917 Am Morgen Strassburg. (Box-folder 108/1)
    - Generalbeichte, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 19.1.68. (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Generalbeichte, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1968. (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Herr, lass mich hungern see Gebet: Herr, lass mich hungern
    - Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich see Gebet: Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke ich
    - Hommage à J. Brahms, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript for piano with emendation (Box-folder 3/8)
    - [J'accuse] 1933, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 8.12.60 Zürich. (Box-folder 4/1)
    - [J'accuse] 1933, Holograph manuscript sketch (Box-folder 4/1)
    - [J'accuse] 1933, Copyist's manuscript full score; On p. 1: Herr Thänning Partitur auf Transparent schreiben / nachher nochmals zur Aussicht O.K. (Box-folder 4/2)
    - J'accuse, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 4/3)
    - J'accuse, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (3 copies); On t.p.: 1933. (Box-folder 4/4)
    - J'accuse, Photocopy of above (Box-folder 4/4)
    - J'accuse 1933, Libretti in German (2 copies) (Box-folder 4/5)
    - I accuse, Libretti in English (2 copies); At end: zum 14-11-67 Otto Freudenthal. (Box-folder 4/5)
    - I accuse, Parts, except strings; Copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 4/6)
    - I accuse, Parts, except strings; Photocopy (2 sets) (Box-folder 4/8-9)
    - I accuse, Parts, strings (Transparencies) (Box-folder 4/7)
    - I accuse, Parts, strings; Photocopy (3 sets) (Box-folder 4/10-12)
    - I accuse, Parts, chorus (Transparencies) (Box-folder 5/1)
    - I accuse, Parts, chorus (Photocopy) (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Juda, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Juda, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Juda, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Juda, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript with emendations (2 copies) (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Juda, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript (3 copies) (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Juda, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Juda, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Juda, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (incomplete) (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Juda, Parts, except strings; Copyist's manuscript (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Juda, Parts, string (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Juda, Libretto with emendations (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Juda, Photocopy of above (2 copies) (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Kinderstück, Photocopy of holograph manuscript for piano; On p. 1: Original bei: M. Mihalovici, 15 rue du Dragon, Paris (6). (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Klavierstück in A Moll, Copyist's manuscript for piano (transparencies) (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Klavierstück in A Moll, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript for piano (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Klavierstück in Gis-Moll, Copyist's manuscript for piano (transparencies) (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Klavierstück in Gis-Moll, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript for piano (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Klavierübung, Copyist's manuscript for piano (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Kreuz der Strasse, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Kreuz der Strasse, Copyist's manuscript full score; On t.p.: 1968. (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Liebeslied, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Liebeslied, Copyist's manuscript full score (2 copies) (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Liebeslied, Parts (Box-folder 3/15)
    - [Lieder]
      - Abglanz, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal sketch; At end: 7.1.68 Z. (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Abglanz, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 3.9.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Abschied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 12.5.62 London Th. A. G. (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Abschied, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 12.5.62 London Th. A. G. (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Allein, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: [illegible inscription]. (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Als Knabe verschlossen see also [Lieder] Grabschrift, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/4)
      - An die Günstigen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 27.8.68 Edinburgh. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 7/5)
      - An L.A., Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/6)
      - An L.A., Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/6)
      - An Lili, Printed piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 7/7)
      - An Lili, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/7)
      - An meine Frau see [Lieder] Ein rascher Sinn
      - An Sonja, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Aus dem Dunkel, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Gedicht von Annie von Mendelssohn; Und ein Mal kommst du doch nach Haus. At end: Zürich, 19.1.67 (komponiert 1907 in Prag.). (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Aus dem Dunkel, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: 1908. At end: [illegible inscription]. (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Aus dem Dunkel, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: [illegible inscription]. (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Aus dem Dunkel, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Aus dem Dunkel, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Aus dem Dunkel, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 106/1)
      - Aus tiefer Not schrei ich zu Dir, Printed piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Aus tiefer Not schrei ich zu Dir, Printed piano-vocal (8 copies) (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Begegnung, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: geschieben um 1909. (Box-folder 7/11)
      - Beherzigung, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/12)
      - Benedictus, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 7/13)
      - Benedictus, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/13)
      - Blick um Blick, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 13.3.70 Zü. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 7/14)
      - Blumengruss, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 25.5.68 Wien. (Box-folder 7/15)
      - Blumengruss, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/15)
      - Contentment, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/16)
      - Dank, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 4.1.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 7/17)
      - Den Seinen giebts der Herr im Schlaft, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/18)
      - Die liebende abermals, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 16.5.68 Wien. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 7/19)
      - Dom [illegible], Orgel, Gesang, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/20)
      - Dort der Galgen, hier die Stricke see [Lieder] Unter Freuden
      - Drei Mignon Lieder, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 9.3.70 Zürich. (Box-folder 7/21)
      - Drei Mignon Lieder, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/21)
      - Du gingst vorüber?, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 11.1.68. (Box-folder 7/22)
      - Du gingst vorüber?, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 5.6.68 Wien. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 7/22)
      - Dehmel, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies) (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Dehmel, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Ein andres, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 25.4.31 Zürich. (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Ein andres, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/2)
      - Entspannung, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 11. April 1933 um 11 Uhr vor Mittag. (Box-folder 8/3)
      - Entspannung, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/3)
      - Er, der einzige Gerechte see [Lieder] Gottes ist der Orient!
      - Erinnerung, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 7.3.70 Zürich. (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Erinnerung, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: (10.4.'68) 10.3.63. (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Erinnerung, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 8.9.68 Z. (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Erinnerung, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 7.2.70 Lorrelon. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Es grüsst dich, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/5)
      - Es ist ein Brunnen der heisst Lied see [Lieder] Gleichnis
      - Es ist gut, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 16.3.70 Zürich. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 8/6)
      - Es war ein alter König, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 23.12.69 Zürich. (Box-folder 8/7)
      - Es war ein alter König, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/7)
      - Es war eine Ratt' im Kellernest, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Es war eine Ratt' im Kellernest, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Es wandert eine schöne Sage see [Lieder] Frühlingsglaube
      - Es war ein König in Thule see [Lieder] Der König in Thule
      - Es war einmal ein König, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Faust music, 2 Lieder (aus Auerbachs Keller). (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Es war einmal ein König see also [Faust], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Feiger Gedanken [version I], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 20.4.71 Zürich. (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Feiger Gedanken [version I], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Feiger Gedanke[n] [version II], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/11)
      - Fort!, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 2.1.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 8/12)
      - Frech und froh, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 10.6.68 Wien. (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Frech und froh, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/13)
      - Frühlingsglaube, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 3.3.67 London. (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Frühlingsglaube, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Frühlingsglaube, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (2 copies); On p. 1: Es wandert eine schöne Sage. Also on p. 1: Studie aus "Das Ziel." (Box-folder 8/14)
      - Fünf andere, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 23.6.68 Z. Laid in: text in German (Box-folder 8/15)
      - Gebet [Herr, mein Gott, der Du erhöret], Printed piano-vocal score; On text p.: Tiefe Ausgabe. (Box-folder 8/16)
      - Gebet [Herr, mein Gott, der Du erhöret], Printed piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Hohe Ausgabe. (Box-folder 8/16)
      - Gebet [Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke] see also Gebet [non-Lieder], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/17)
      - Gebet [Herr, mein Gott Dir danke ich] see also Gebet [non-Lieder], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript flute-voice score with emendations (Box-folder 8/18)
      - Gebet [Lass mich in Dir bleiben], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 9-12-67 Zürich. (Box-folder 8/19)
      - Gebet [Lass mich in Dir bleiben], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/19)
      - Gebet [Was soll werden], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/20)
      - Gefunden, Printed piano-vocal score with emendations; On cover: Ich ging im Walde. (Box-folder 8/21)
      - Der Genesene an die Hoffnung, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 8/22)
      - Gleichnis, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: Es ist Brunnen der heisst Lied. At end: 15.11.67 London. (Box-folder 8/23)
      - Gleichnis, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: Es ist ein Brunnen. (Box-folder 8/23)
      - Glückes genug, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 10.6.60 Zürich. (Box-folder 8/24)
      - Glückes genug, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/24)
      - Glückes genug, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies) (Box-folder 8/24)
      - Glückes genug, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (3 copies) (Box-folder 8/24)
      - Gottes ist der Orient!, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Er, der einzige Gerechte. At end: 10.6.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 8/25)
      - Grabschrift see also [Lieder] Als Knabe verschlossen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p. and p. 1: Als Knabe verschlossen. At end: 5.6.68 Wien. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 8/26)
      - Hab ich tausend Mal geschworen [version 1], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 19.1.70 London. (Box-folder 9/1)
      - Hab ich tausend Mal geschworen [version 1], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Hab' ich tausend Mal geschworen [version 2], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations; At end: 1970. (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Hab' mein Lieb so Lieb, Printed manuscript piano-vocal score; On text p.: Dr. Heinrich Simon (Inhaber der Frankfurter Zeitung). (Box-folder 9/4)
      - Harfenspieler [Wer nie sein Brot], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 21.4.71. (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Harfenspieler [Wer nie sein Brot], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: Copyright 1971 by Otto Klemperer. (Box-folder 9/5)
      - Harfenspieler [Wer sich der Einsamkeit], Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 1.7.68 Z. (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Harfenspieler [Wer sich der Einsamkeit], Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Hatem, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 15.1.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/7)
      - Heiss' mich nicht reden see [Lieder] Drei Mignon Leider
      - Herr, mein Gott, der Du erhöret see [Lieder] Gebet [Herr, mein Gott, der Du erhöret]
      - Herr, mein Gott, Dir danke see [Lieder] Gebet [Herr, mein Gott Dir danke]
      - Hochbeglückt in deiner Liebe see [Lieder] Suleika
      - Hochzeitlied, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: (Buenos Aires 1951). (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Ich ging am frühen morgen aus see [Lieder] Wie ein Volkslied
      - Ich ging im Walde see [Lieder] Gefunden
      - Ich habe, lieben Brüder, ein gutes Haus bewohnt, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: Zürich 1. Februar 1967. (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Ich habe, lieben Brüder, ein gutes Haus bewohnt, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 9/9)
      - Ich will mich im grünen Wald ergehen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: Zürich 21.1.67. (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Ich will mich im grünen Wald ergehen, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: B-dur; Hohe Lage. (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Ich will mich im grünen Wald ergehen, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: As-dur; mittel-Lage. (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Ich will mich im grünen Wald ergehen, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On t.p.: Ges-dur; Tiefe Lage. (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Ja, die Augen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 7.6.65 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/11)
      - Kennst du das Land see [Lieder] Drei Mignon Lieder
      - Klagen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 23.12.67 Z. (Box-folder 9/12)
      - Der König in Thule, Photocopy of holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; In margins: Original im Moldenhauer Archiv, University of Illinois; 1973. (Box-folder 9/13)
      - Der König in Thule, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/13)
      - Der König in Thule, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/13)
      - Kreuz der Strasse, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (2 copies); Laid in: photocopy of letter in German from Wolfgang Osthoff to Lotte Klemperer. (Box-folder 9/14)
      - Lass mich in Dir bleiben see [Lieder] Gebet [Lass mich in Dir bleiben]
      - Das Leben ist ein schlechter Spass, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 17.4.71. (Box-folder 9/15)
      - Das Leben ist ein schlechter Spass, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/15)
      - Lebensregel see [Lieder] Willst du dir ein hübsch' Leben zimmern
      - Lesebuch, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 26.4.68 Z. (Box-folder 9/16)
      - Lesebuch, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 17.1.70 London. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/16)
      - Lieb um Liebe, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 1.7.68 Z. Laid in: text in German. (Box-folder 9/17)
      - Eine liebe Stunde, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: Zürich 26.1.67. Also on t.p. and p. 1: Die liebe Stunde. (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Eine liebe Stunde, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score; On p. 1: Meiner Marianne in inniger Liebe zum 10. Februar 1913. (Box-folder 9/18)
      - Die Liebende schreibt, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: London 62. (Box-folder 9/19)
      - Die Liebende schreibt, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 9/19)
      - Liebeslied, Printed piano-vocal score with emendations; On t.p.: (aus einem Opernentwurf). Also on t.p.: 21./3. 17. (Box-folder 9/20)
      - Liebeslied, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/20)
      - Lied, Printed piano-vocal score (2 copies); On cover: Ungesucht gefunden. (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Lied, Photocopy of printed piano-vocal score; On text p.: Hohe Ausgabe. (Box-folder 9/21)
      - Märchen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 5.10.68 London. Laid in: text in German (Box-folder 9/22)
      - Mag sie sich immer ergänzen, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: 30.6.68 Z. (Box-folder 9/23)